Hello and welcome to another episode of Elephant
English podcasts. Today I am going to talk about
my daily routines. I normally do the same things
every week but some days I do different things.
In the United Kingdom, Sunday is normally the
first day on the calendar, so I am going to
tell you what I normally do on Sundays first.
For me, Sundays are for resting and relaxing. In
the morning, I clean the living room, the kitchen
and the bathroom. When I have finished cleaning,
I make lunch. I normally cook a lot of food
because then I can eat it on Monday or Tuesday,
for example, and that way I don’t have to cook
every day. In the afternoon, I usually watch
the Formula 1 race, but there aren’t races every
week. Finally, in the evening, I prepare my
classes for the week because I am a teacher.
Mondays, Tuesdays, Wednesdays and Thursdays are
very similar for me, but Mondays are definitely
the worst day of the week. I don’t like Mondays
because I am very tired and because the days feel
very long. When I wake up on these days, I brush
my teeth, I get dressed, I brush my hair, I have
breakfast and then I go to work at 7.30am.
I always have my lunch at work because
then I don’t have to prepare it. In the UK,
people normally have breakfast in the morning
after they wake up and they normally have some
cereals and milk and a cup of coffee or a cup
of tea. Then, at 12 o’clock or 1 o’clock they
have their lunch, which is normally a sandwich, a
salad or something else that is quite small.
I come home at 5pm and after that I
sometimes have extra English classes
in the evenings. I normally have dinner and
before I go to bed I play with my cat because
she has got a lot of energy. If I don’t play
with my cat, she doesn’t sleep at night, so
this is an important thing for me to do.
In the UK people normally have dinner
at 6 o’clock or a bit later, when they
come back from work. This is the biggest
meal of the day and the typical British dinner
is a roast dinner, which includes some meat,
chicken or fish, some potatoes, some vegetables
like carrots, broccoli or peas. However,
people obviously don’t eat this every day,
and they might eat a pasta dinner, curry,
a pie or something like that. Before going to bed,
some people have a snack that is called supper.
Depending on if you are hungry or not, people
will have a bigger or a smaller supper.
On Fridays, I am normally happier because
it is the weekend. In the evening I go for
a walk or watch a series on Netflix. I like
Fridays but I don’t have a lot of energy
so I normally relax and stay at home.
Finally, I normally eat out on Saturdays.
My favorite type of restaurants are Italian
restaurants because I love pasta and pizza.
After having dinner, I go to the supermarket or to
the shopping center because I like to buy the food
that I will eat during the week.
So, today I have talked to you about what
I normally do every week. Sometimes I do other
different things, like going to the mountains
or visiting a new city, but this is
just a typical week for me.
What are your daily routines? What do you
normally do at the weekend? Tell me what you
normally do every week in the comment section
for me to read. You can find the transcription
and activities related to this topic in
the description box. Please like this video
and subscribe to my channel if you liked
the video. Thank you and see you next time!