in the past few months there has been a surge of interest in the outdoors
and in particular wild camping
while much of this has been done responsibly
there has been a lot of cases where people have camped in appropriately
leaving their equipment and their litter behind like a scar on the countryside
instead of moaning about the problem
i thought i'd be proactive
and provide an insight into how i camp responsibly some of the gear that i use
and some of the choices i make while out on a camp and hopefully
by doing this can help any future wild campers make sensible choices
i arrived fairly late last night
which is good practice if you want to be discreet
i picked a nice level spot far away from any footpaths
with good cover from the wind
here i'm using a sit pad that i made out of some old foam
and insulation foil it helps to keep my bone warm and dry
and weighs a heck of a lot less than a camping chair
this is the container i use to hold methylated spirit
which i use as fuel for my stove
stove that i'm using on this trip
is the alp kit brewer which costs around 25 pound from the applique website
i don't usually bother with a kettle
as this 750ml pot can boil enough water for a coffee and some food
while also keeping a relatively low pack size and weight
i recently bought this three-piece cutlery set from go outdoors
for around two pound fifty
and i've been really impressed with it
it came with me on a week-long trip to scotland
and worked really well for me
a really handy tip if you are heading out wild camping
is to take a couple of ziplock bags
they are really good for storing food
and even better for storing your rubbish afterwards
the fact that they have a zip
means that no rubbish will get in your bag
and any smells will be kept to a minimum
i always like to pack a small cloth in my kit
for drying out cups and pans after using them
i'll sometimes even use it to dry off any items that happen to get wet
if i'm camping on my own then i always pack two head torches
this one was around 10 pound from amazon
i won't go into too much detail about sleeping bags
as they really are a personal preference
just be sure to pick up a bag with the right temperature ratings for the season you want to use it
the sleeping setup that i use
is a combination of a sleeping bag
pillow and inflatable mat
all of this sits on top of a standard foam roll pad
another little handy tip
is to put all of your bags for your sleep system and gear
into your empty tent bag
that way it's really easy to find when packing away in the morning
this is a great little inflatable pillow from trichology
i picked this one up due to the soft removable cover that it comes with
the sleeping pad that i'm using
is another one from trackology
and to be honest it's the best pad that i've ever used
any old bit of elastic can come in really handy
when trying to keep your foam roll mat rolled up and secure
the tent i use is the lunch on two
which uses trekking poles to pitch instead of traditional temples
it's a very affordable lightweight tent
and can be found on the aliexpress website
the blue sheet i'm using here is a footprint to help protect the base of the tent
i cut this myself from a cheap bit of tarpaulin
now we're all packed away it's time to start packing the rucksack
i usually start with my sleeping bag intent stuffed into the bottom of my pack
i then usually follow this with any bit of clothing
cookware or cutlery that needs to go in
and of course don't forget to pack your ziploc bag full of your rubbish
once you're packed away and ready to go
it's always a good idea to do a quick sweep of the area
just to check that you haven't left anything behind
i hope you enjoyed this video
and managed to take something useful from it
i feel that now more than ever
we need to be trying our hardest as a collective to keep our countryside clean and tidy
if you are considering your first wild camp
then please act responsibly
and help to look after our beautiful countryside
finally i would love to hear your feedback in the comments below
feel free to ask me any questions if you feel i've missed something
and let me know if you'd like to see more of this style of video in the future
take care and thanks for watching