The perfect launch.
And a controlled drop.
This is as good a descent
as it's possible to make.
Its parents are there to meet it.
A little dazed perhaps,
but all in one piece.
One gosling, at least, hasn't made it.
And this chick appears to be in a bad way.
At last, it responds
to its mother's calls.
The resilience of a barnacle goose chick
is extraordinary.
But there are still chicks
unaccounted for,
somewhere amongst the rubble.
The parents can't risk searching
because they need to lead
their two survivors away quickly,
before predators arrive.
A third one has made it.
But it needs to catch up.
Reunited.
Three out of five chicks have made it.
Without such a dramatic start in life,
it's unlikely any of them
would have even got this far.