This is the real english conversations podcast
Where you'll find the advice you need to be able to confidently use your English in the real world.
Hi everybody, this is Amy from Real English Conversations and I'm here with Curtis.
Hi everybody!
And today, we are going to tell you all
about how you can predict your future or tell fortunes
So there's four main or common ways
that people tell fortunes in American culture. What are they?
They are palm reading, tarot cards, tea leaves and astrology.
Alright. And there are some less known ways which I found today when I was on Wikipedia
learning a little bit about fortune telling. And I thought that I would talk about them.
So, the first one is roosters pecking grain which I imagine is just a plate
maybe in front of the rooster and he eats his food and then after there is a pattern and it is interpreted somehow.
And another one, a little bit more gruesome, is reading the livers of sacrificed animals.
Oooh, yeah. That sounds like something from the medieval days.
Yeah, definitely. And the last one which is the most disgusting of all, is reading animal poop.
Eeew.
I don't know whose animal poop they are reading or how you become an expert in that,
but it’s definitely not a profession that I want.
Sounds gross.
So why don’t you tell us a little bit
about palm reading?
Okay, palm reading is a way of telling your future or your past depending on
So why don’t you tell us a little bit
about palm reading?
Okay, palm reading is a way of telling your future or your past depending on
the lines and designs in the palm of your hand.
And there's many of them. There's a life line,
a love line, so many of them I can't remember
all of them but yeah, based on the length
or the size or the shape of these patterns
that would explain what has happened in your past or what could be happening in your future.
And the next one is tarot cards. So with
tarot card reading, what happens is,
if you are having your fortune being told, you have
the deck of cards and you shuffle them
and mix them up a bit and then you put the deck
together, cut the deck at whatever point you want
which is just separating the deck into
two and then you hand it to the person
Who is reading your cards. They lay out the cards
in some sort of order and they are based on
which is just separating the deck into
two and then you hand it to the person
Who is reading your cards. They lay out the cards
in some sort of order and they are based on
the symbols or the characters that are on these cards.
They are going to determine your future or your fortune.
Based on the different images.
That's right and I think the next one
is really good for Curtis to explain
Because it is about tea leaf reading. And this is
something that I can remember his mom doing
during special occasions like Christmas or
Thanksgiving after dinner when we were drinking tea.
Because it is about tea leaf reading. And this is
something that I can remember his mom doing
during special occasions like Christmas or
Thanksgiving after dinner when we were drinking tea.
So how does it go?
Well it is a special way of preparing tea.
Obviously it’s loose leaf tea. So it’s not from a tea bag.
The tea leaves are floating around in the pot.
Because you want to make sure that they can get into the cup, right?
Right. So when it is poured,
the leaf will or the leaves will fall into the cup and you normally leave
a bit of tea in the bottom of your cup and
swirl it around and then you turn it over
and after you turn it over, you turn it three
times in a certain direction.
Like on the saucer.
Turning it with the cup upside down,
going one, two, three for turns.
And then you turn back the cup up
back over again so it's right side up.
And then our famous tea leaf reader,
Marilyn...
she even had a book.
Yeah, to be able to identify the different shapes
and she knew... I can't remember what it was but I think if it's close to the rim
of the cup, it was happening sooner.
Or if it was close to the handle of
the cup. Yeah you look into the cup
and you will see different patterns and you know, like, I think she saw a rooster or tree or something
Yeah, your future or things, once
again that have happened in your past
are revealed through those patterns.
I think the patterns are for the future though.
We are talking about
No All of them we are talking about predicting
your future, not the past.
True, True
So anyway, that's about tea leaf reading.
Right.
And what is astrology about?
Okay. Astrology is about different
signs that are based on the planets
and the stars, the sun, the moon and your birthday as well.
Alright and depending on your birthday particularly.
There's something that you'll see, it's like a horoscope.
And they are published often in newspapers.
And depending on what your zodiac sign is,
you have a horoscope which is a prediction on how your day is gonna go.
Right. So what are the twelve zodiac signs?
There are twelve zodiac signs and they are: Aquarius, Pisces, Aries, Taurus,
Gemini, Cancer, Leo, Virgo, Libra, Scorpio, Sagittarius and Capricorn.
And which sign are you?
I am a Virgo. But I am on what is called the cusp.
So my birthday falls on the last day of Virgo
but the next day of Libra is the day after my birthday.
So sometimes, Curtis’s horoscope is
more accurate for Libra,
And sometimes it's more accurate to Virgo.
Because you could
imagine if you were born on September 22nd at 11PM at night.
You are only one hour away
from the next zodiac sign which is Libra.
So, in theory you should have personality
tendencies or your luck,
if you pay attention to these things and believe it, would be more
of a Libra influence.
And you are a Gemini.
I am a Gemini which is supposed to be
the dual personality so I don't know.
I think I'm really, really nice most of the time but
I can definitely be mean and evil from time to time
Really?
Curtis pretends he never sees it.
Anyway, how about you read our forecast or our horoscope for today?
Okay, I'm going to start with yours.
And yours is, let me just bring this up. Here we go
Brainstorming with other people could
lead to incredible solutions.
And if you are a Gemini who is a business person, that requires
a lot of creative energy, it will blossom today.
That sounds like a good day for me to
do some business work and hopefully be successful
and talk to some people. And what is your horoscope?
Mine for today?
Is this Virgo or Libra?
This is Virgo.
Okay, so your real horoscope.
An intense emotional dream could move you so powerfully
that you wake with the odd sense
that the dream was rea l. Write it down, Virgo!
Efforts to overcome obstacles and advance
yourself in your career could finally be paying off
Wow. That's actually interesting because in that list of ways of predicting the future,
there was one that was based on dreams.
So maybe you should write down whatever your dream was last night and then we should find a dream reader
and then we'll know even more about your future.
That's exciting.
Yeah. So, astrology I actually had a
period of time where I was really interested
in astrology and I had this book which was,
I think it was called, "The Only Astrology Book You'll Ever Need"
and it was pretty thorough.
It's like a textbook with 300 pages or something.
it was huge, I remember. It was a really, big book.
And it factored all the aspects
of astrology
down to the time that you were born.
So if you were born at 11 o'clock on
this day, and this year,
I guess the sun was in this position and the moon was in that position,
and some planet was flying around the universe
It had different influences on you.
And after you had calculated everything,
you read a couple of different pages,
and it described in detail about your character,
And after you had calculated everything,
your personality, your tendencies, the habits
that you have,
the things that you like or you don't like.
Really in a lot of detail.
And the first time that I seen this book was actually a friend of mine
and I was blown away with it's accuracy.
I thought it was probably 90% accurate
but not vague like these horoscopes.
These could be applicable for anybody.
Like you could have a powerful brainstorming day.
I could.
And I could have had a strange dream.
Right.
That I should write down.
But this book that you are talking about, it was more accurate. It was like almost like you wrote about it.
Yeah, wrote about myself and if you were to I gave my horoscope
to you and said, this is yours, and just change the title at the top,
you'd be like, "Well, this isn't like me at all."
But his was really, really accurate as well.
Especially because he was on the cusp.
It was more of a proper horoscope
instead of the blend or having to read one and then read the other one
because it was down to the day.
It was very accurate.
So that's where my opinion changed a little bit about astrology.
I don't think that I would be willing to base my life decisions on it.
You weren’t skeptical.
Well I'm still, I think it's interesting, I think it's insanely accurate. I don't know how.
It's a little bit of a mystery.
But what would be really cool is if you could leave us a comment below,
and telling us what your zodiac sign is.
If you don't know, just type in to Google zodiac sign
and it will have a set of dates and you just need to determine
which day your birthday falls on.
Yeah.
And then you will know what your zodiac sign is.
And maybe you could do some English reading practice
Exactly.
And learn what your future has in store.
Okay guys. So there are 3 things we want you to do right now
The first one is to subscribe to our youtube channel
To get more helpful tips just like this one
and the second one is to make sure you give us the thumbs up
if you like these tips and you want to see more
just give us the thumbs up
There's actually 4 things
The third thing is to leave us a comment
Hello, say hello, we love to hear from you
And the last thing is to follow this link
That's right here on the video
To make sure that you join our email list Where we send you some lessons Specifically related to speaking
so that you can get some more advice
and tips about how you can become an excellent English speaker with Real English Conversations
yep. We'll see you next time!
Bye Guys