It’s early morning,
and we are walking on a cobblestone street
towards a fairytale like castle.
It seems as though we are walking on a bridge or a raised street
which leads right to the entrance of the castle...
...right to these closed wooden doors.
The medieval castle in front of us
is named Eltz Castle (or Burg Eltz).
It’s nestled in the hills on the western side of Germany,
in the federal state of Rhineland-Pfalz.
means to be located in the hills,
near to the hills,
almost like the hills are holding the castle gently.
The oldest part of this castle dates to the 9th century.
It expanded as the centuries passed.
This picture was taken in the early morning
and the castle is surrounded by thick fog,
which definitely gives the place a mystical
or even spooky feeling to it.
The hills in the background are covered in dark trees
and we can only see the hints of the rising sun
starting to light up some clouds.
The castle has many small windows,
fairy-tale like spires and turrets,
and pointy A-frame roofs.
We can see some flags or banners flying on the top of the castle,
held up high into the air by metal spires.
These pointy things are called spires.
There is some reconstruction or maintenance going on over here,
on the right side of the castle.
We can see some scaffolding set up next to the castle walls .
There is a small stone tower
peaking out of the fog over here on the right,
and the dark forests and fog add to the loneliness one feels in this image.
It’s a time of the day to dream
and remember the past,
long before the tourist crowds come rumbling down this road.
The fog almost makes us feel like we are falling out of time… into the past.
It’s possible to visit the castle today.
It is still owned by a branch of the same family
that lived there in the 12th century…
thirty-three generations later.
If you are old enough,
you may also remember that this castle was on the 500 Detusche mark note,
from 1965 to 1992.
I wonder how many of those notes one would need to buy this castle…
For more photo descriptions, check out one of these videos
and remember: COMMUNICATION FIRST... ALWAYS!